

Pankaj Chopra

Pega Lead System
Architect/Technical Program
Manager/Development Lead



Summary

Pankaj is a certified CLSA I with +13 years of IT experience, +10 years in Pega PRPC v8.x, v7.x, v6.x in multiple domains. He has done pioneering work in Analytics, Decisioning, Reporting & Dashboard, Application User-Interface including mobile devices. Pankaj has developed many underlying components in Pega's CRM & Sales-Automation suites of framework while working with Pegasystem. He has participated in various online ([Top-Coder], HackerRank, Techgig etc) & offline competitions, e.g., Puzzles, Algorithm Designs & Problem solving contests.

Pankaj holds a master's degree with distinction in Computer Science from India's prestigious college NIT and bachelor's degree in Mathematics from Ramjas College (University of Delhi), where he was a college topper. Pankaj has an excellent academic performance throughout.



Work History

2022-06 -Current

ISD Developer V

Navy Federal Credit Union, Pensacola, FL

- Major involvement as development-lead and Pega SME in automating SCRA (Service member Civil Relief Act) for 5 products - Credit card, CLOC, Consumer loan, Student loan and Mortgage
- Collaborated on stages of systems development lifecycle from requirement gathering to production releases for legacy SCRA lotus notes app to Pega application on Cloud.



Address

Pensacola, FL 32526

Phone

773-225-0765

E-mail

pc06matt@gmail.com

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/pankajchopra



Inter team Coordination & Planning



Pega-PRPC



Reporting & Dashboard



Application Design & Class Structure



Case Management



UI-Mobile, UIKit, Client Performance Expert



Artificial Intelligence, CDH, Decisioning



cisioning • • •

- Help design and develop huge workflows for SCRA process involving active duty member.
- Tech-stack included: Updating Microsoft
 Dynamics Power-platform using azure service bus
- Tech-stack included: Mulesoft API subscriptions and implementation using Pega REST connectors for all vendor APIs including TSYS, Blacknight and NF-Internal.
- Design and develop components in Vertical SCRA implementation as well as Horizontal Enterprise framework in NF.
- Negotiated with vendors, partners and contractors to secure contracts and set SLAs

2019-10 -2022-06

Pega Lead System Architect (Client: Verizon)

Ciberspring International, Dallas, TX

- Design & implemented horizontal framework 'Global-Decision-Engine' for 3 decisioning applications.
- Design & implemented 'Health-Check' tool in horizontal framework, which is being used by all 3 applications.
- Part of application upgrade from Pega v8.3.3 to Pega v8.5.5
- Migration of DSM (legacy) to CDH (NBA-Designer) module in Pega-MKT for COMMs.
- Design & implemented the Pega-Kafka-Kibana implementation for log-management (Service & Connector request-response) for troubleshooting, reporting and auditing.
- Developed horizontal dashboard in Kibana for business as well as operations.
- Audience simulation design and implementation for A/B Testing along with Operation-Management for Citizen developers.

Responsibilities - Started as LSA in one of decisionapplication in Verizon. Now, leading the Center-Of-Excellence team across 3 implementation Pega-MKT (decisioning) applications. Help teams with designs, review the implementation, developing components that can be used across multiple Microsoft Dynamics Power platform





Technical Grooming - Pre Sprint & Backlog

Fusion Charts

Icons framework e.g.
Fontawesome, Budicons

Algorithm & Design Patterns

Java, J2EE, DHTML

Web services with Java

PL-SQL

CSS Frameworks, e.g. Bootstrap, UIKit

Azure Service Bus, Kafka

decisioning application and document them. Help leadership understanding the technical components and also help in PI sessions with business.

2018-04 -2019-09

Pega System Architect (Client: American Express)

CTI Infotech Inc., Phoenix, AZ

- Design and implemented headless Pega
 Approach (Orchestrator) and End-To-End Pega
 Approach (Risk Underwriting).
- Design & implemented Case Management (cases) & Data Modeling (data types, data pages, decision rules) in Pega v7.4
- Helped in Upgrading application from Pega v7.1 to Pega v7.4
- Incorporated Fontawesome & Budicons Icon frameworks in the global FW layer to be used by different applications
- Implemented Spark chart win/loss solution for financial information using inbuilt fusion-chart JavaScript library and DHTML.
- Designed the Security Audit tracking & history logging for all cases.

Responsibilities - Provide architectural solutions for BPM automation applications, design communication between them & help them developing the features in AGILE scrum delivery model.

Achievement - Successfully implemented 'Pega Mobile Client' on Company-Owned-Device powered using Tunnel VPN. Provided solutions for lighter UI-Skin & best practices across the application, including performance analysis by adding advanced functions (Embed-UserFunction, java function & JSP controls).

2014-04 -2018-03

Principal Solution Engineer

Pegasystems Worldwide India Pvt. Ltd., Hyderabad, Telangana

 Worked as SME for best-practices in implementing Pega Sales-Automation, in TCS Chennai for client

- AIG Japan for 6 months; mentoring team of 40 developers.
- Led more than 5 prototype projects successfully for Pega prospects with pre-sales team.
- Involved in upgrade of AIG Japan Insurance project from Pega v6.3 to Pega v7.1
- 'Reporting & Dashboard' feature tech-lead in CRM unit (across 3 scrum teams) & supported 8 implementations for this feature. This feature included 'Dashboard Personalization' with +40 widgets & Report-browser with +50 OOTB reports.
- 'Bulk Migration' feature tech-lead in CRM unit (across 3 scrum teams) & supported 3 implementations. This feature included bulk migration of cases to Pega from competitors, e.g. 'Microsoft Dynamics', Salesforce.com, etc.
- End-to-End involvement for Pega CRM & Sales-Automation framework, from inception of feature to deployment with post-deployment support.
- Extensively worked on UI & UX (including hybrid mobile app & i-Pad compatibility) in Pega 7.x (latest 7.4 ver)
- Helped in designing Pega-World Sample application from scratch using Dynamic Class Referencing pattern.
- Solid understanding of Pega CRM & Pega Sales-Automation framework.
- Experience in troubleshooting & performance tuning of PRPC production applications using Clipboard, Tracer and Performance Analyzer (PAL).
- Designed & developed B2B, B2C & B2B+B2C business generic model for Sales-Automation horizontal framework.

Responsibilities - Design & Development of new features as part of horizontal framework & supporting more than 8 vertical teams across CRM. Leading pre-sprint & backlog technical grooming. Help Sales-Consulting to develop the POCs, design & development issues related CRM framework.

Achievement - "Most Ready to Ship!" winner for Pega-Hackathon7 project organized in Feb 2018

leading 3 team members

2012-09 -2014-03

Application Developer

Oracle India Pvt. Ltd., Hyderabad, Telangana

- Worked on pipeline early spring framework for Primavera-P6 web application.
- Helped in creating Log-in page on JSP with HTML4
 & JQuery.
- Good understanding of Unifier BPM architecture and design.
- Created many algorithmic and problem solving functions for proficient application in java.

2010-01 -2012-08

Systems Engineer

Infosys Ltd., Hyderabad, Telangana

- Part of Work Force Management team providing solutions in Infor-Workbrain, Kronos & Oracle enterprise applications.
- Participate in System requirements gathering,
 OOA/Design and UML modeling.
- Proposed technical feasibility solutions for new system designs and suggested options for performance improvement of around 30% technical components



Education

2001-05 -2010-06

Master of Computer Applications: Computer And Information Sciences

Maulana Azad National Institute of Technology - Bhopal, MP

- Professional development completed in Neural networks
- 8.63 CGPA

Bachelor of Science: Mathematics

Ramjas College, Delhi University - New Delhi

8.17 CGPA

Awarded College topper in second year through Delhi University

Certifications

Pega Certified Lead System Architect (CLSA I) v7.x

Pega Certified Senior System Architect (CSSA) v7.x

2014-04 Pega Certified System Architect (CSA) v7.x